Nishant Raj

(Senior Engineer Planning)

Address: Vill- Darhatar, P.O+P.S.- Itki, Ranchi, Jharkhand, Pin Code- 835301 Email: Nishantr53@gmail.com

D.O.B.: 18/01/1990 Contact: 8830081695



CAREER OBJECTIVE

Currently working as sr. engineer planning & monitoring with experience of more than three years and two-month in infrastructure project, and ten-month experience in real estate. I have total experience of four years. I'm post graduated in Project Engineering Management from NICMAR-Pune. Looking for job switch in an organization where I can use skill and experience for the growth of organization and will work as team in achieving organizational goals and targets efficiently and successfully.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

YEAR	QUALIFICATION	COLLEGE/UNIVERSITY	MARKS
2016-18	PGP Project Engineering & Management	National Institute of Construction Management and Research, Pune	6.86 CPI
2010-14	B.E. (Civil)	Annamalai University, Chidambaram	7.12 OGPA
2010	12th	LMNS Inter College Itki, Ranchi (Jharkhand Academic Council)	56.80%
2008	10th	DAV Public School, Ranchi (CBSE)	64.17%

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Organization	Hindustan Construction Company Ltd., Mumbai	Feb-2021- Present
Designation	Senior Engineer (Planning)	
Project Name	Construction of Tunnel T-13, Part Tunnel T-14 including Station Yard at Basindadhar, Approach Road from ADIT of T-13 (Khanikote) to P2 of T-13 & P-1 of T-14 (Basindadhar) and Bridge No 60 (between KM 61.004 to KM 73.784 approx.) on Katra - Banihal Section of Udhampur-Srinagar-Baramulla New BG Railway Line Project (Package T-13)	
Role	As planning engineer, I have to make schedule of work for upcoming months and monitor them time to time, prepare budget, make monthly progress report and daily progress report, book DPR, client bill and subcontract bill in SAP, prepare client bill and subcontractor bill, estimate the quantities required for work, involved in daily correspondence with client.	
Organization	GR Infra Limited, Udaipur	May 2019- June 2020
Designation	Assistant Manager (Planning Monitoring)	
Project Name	Two Laning with Paved shoulders of Biharsharif-Barbigha-Mo	kama Section of NH-82

Role	Working as assistant manager in Planning and monitoring department. Make monthly program in which we have to plan for the work to be done also major materials required to complete that work. Keep record of daily progress also submit the report to the management. Work as team and communicate with the person working at site. Sometimes help in making client bill and attend the meeting with client to discuss about any changes to be made for ongoing or upcoming works.		
Organization	GR Infra Limited, Udaipur	May 2018-April 2019	
Designation	Management Trainee		
Project Name	Two Laning with Paved shoulders of Biharsharif-Barbigha-Mokama Section of NH-82		
Role	Make production report, Material and item reconciliation, Work on ERP system (SAP), Make sales order and purchase order, do reservation of different materials for subcontractor, making daily, weekly and office reports, Raising Inspection Requests and Checking for client, Tracking activities as per plan.		
Organization	BL Kashyap, Bangalore	Dec 2014- Sept 2015	
Designation	GTE		
Project Name	Embassy Pristine, Bangalore		
Role	Site Execution, Quantity Estimation, making daily, weekly and office reports, Raising Inspection Requests and Checking for client, tracking activities as per plan, fixing small problems of client, Giving details of ongoing work details to project manager.		

INTERNSHIP UNDERTAKEN

Organization	Orange City Water, Nagpur	April 2017- June 2017
Project Name	24*7 Water supply scheme	
Role	Lodging complains of customers, providing new connection, office & site work, meeting cooperators, fixing leakages, looking at distribution channels.	

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Project Name	Comparative analysis of revenue gap, consumer profile and power availability indicators of selected distribution utilities in India.
Description:	Analysis of different consumer profile and revenue gap was done for the state of Jharkhand and Gujarat. And relation was made between them.
Project Name	Absorption of dyes from textile industry
Description:	Algae were used for cleaning of dye water from textile industry.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Member of Kabaddi team in school

SOFTWARE SKILLS

Presentation Tools - MS Office, MSP, SAP, AutoCAD 2D, Primavera

INTEREST AND HOBBIES

Travelling, Cooking, Listening to music

LANGUAGES KNOWN

English, Hindi

I hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge. Nishant Raj